{
    "questions": [
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 1,
            "question": "\"Which Code sample will eventually cause the computer to run out of memory?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\nwhile(1)\n{\nchar *smallString = (char *) malloc(10);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nlong long number = 1;\nwhile(1)\nnumber *= 2;\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nwhile(1)\n{\nchar hugeString[1000000L];\nmemset(hugeString, 0, 1000000L);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nwhile(1)\n{\nlong *bigArray = (long *) malloc(sizeof(long) * 1000);\nmemset(bigArray, 1000000, 1000);\n\n(bigArray);\n}\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 2,
            "question": "\"What will this code print on the screen?\"",
            "body": "```c\nint f1 (int a, int b)\n{\n    if (a > b)\n    {\n        printf(\"A is greater than B\\n\");\n        return 1;\n    }\n    else\n    {\n        printf(\"B is greater than A\");\n        return 0;\n    }\n}\n\nmain()\n{\n    if (f1(20,10) || f1(10,20))\n        printf(\"C is fun!\\n\");\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```\nA is greater then B\nC is fun!\n```",
                ":",
                "```\nA is greater then B\nB is greater then A\nC is fun!\n```",
                ":",
                "```\nA is greater then B\nB is greater then A\n```",
                "Nothing is printed on Screen"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 3,
            "question": "\"What is the name for calling a function inside the same function?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"recursion\"",
            "choices": [
                "recursion",
                "subfunction",
                "inner call",
                "infinite loop"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 4,
            "question": "\"What does the declaration of variable c2 demonstrate?\"",
            "body": "```c\nmain(){\n    char c1 ='a';\n    char c2 = c1+10;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"character arithmetic\"",
            "choices": [
                "character arithmetic",
                "undefined assignment",
                "type conversion",
                "invalid declaration"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 5,
            "question": "\"What is this declaration an example of?\"",
            "body": "```c\nstruct s {\n    int i;\n    struct s *s1;\n    struct s *s2;\n};\n```",
            "answer": "\"a node\"",
            "choices": [
                "a node",
                "a linked list",
                "a stack",
                "a binary tree"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 6,
            "question": "\"Header files are listed using the preprocessing directive #include, and can have one of the following formats: #include &lt;fileA&gt; or #include \"fileB\". What is the difference between these two formats?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"The preprocessor will try to locate fileA in a predetermined directory path. It will try to locate fileB in the same directory as the source file along with a custom directory path.\"",
            "choices": [
                "The preprocessor will try to locate fileA in same directory as the source file, and the fileB in a predetermined directory path.",
                "The preprocessor will try to locate fileA in the fixed system directory. It will try to locate fileB in the directory path designated by the -I option added to the command line while compiling the source code.",
                "The file using the fileA syntax must be system files, of unlimited number; fileB must be a user file at a maximun of one per source file.",
                "The preprocessor will try to locate fileA in a predetermined directory path. It will try to locate fileB in the same directory as the source file along with a custom directory path."
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 7,
            "question": "\"Using a for loop, how could you write a C code to count down from 10 to 1 and display each number on its own line?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\nfor (int i = 0; i>=0, i--){\nprintf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n}//end of loop\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nint i;\nfor (i=1; i<=10; i++){\nprintf(\"%d\", i);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nint i = 10;\nwhile (i>0){\nprintf(\"%d\\n\", i);\ni--;\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nint i;\nfor (i= 10; i>0; i--){\nprintf(\"%d\\n\", i);\n}// end of loop\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 8,
            "question": "\"What is not one of the reserved words in standard C?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"typeof\"",
            "choices": [
                "volatile",
                "typeof",
                "register",
                "typedef"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 9,
            "question": "\"What does the program shown below return?\"",
            "body": "```c\nint main(){\n    int a=1, b=2, c=3, d=4;\n    int x = a;\n    if (a>b)\n    if (b<c) x=b;\n    else x=c;\n    return(x);\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"1\"",
            "choices": [
                "1",
                "3",
                "2",
                "0"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 10,
            "question": "\"Using the Union declaration below, how many bytes of memory space will the data of this type occupy?\"",
            "body": "```c\nunion Cars {\n    char make[20];\n    char model[30];\n    short year;\n} car;\n```",
            "answer": "\"30\"",
            "choices": [
                "32",
                "54",
                "30",
                "52"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 11,
            "question": "\"In this code sample, what is not a problem for C compiler?\"",
            "body": "```c\nmain(){\n    constant int PI = 3.14;\n    printf(\"%f\\n\", pi);\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"The value of PI needs to be set to 3.141593, not 3.14\"",
            "choices": [
                "The value of PI needs to be set to 3.141593, not 3.14",
                "The declaration of PI needs to say const, not constant.",
                "The data type of PI needs to be float not int.",
                "The printf statement needs to use PI, not pi."
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 12,
            "question": "\"Which is the smallest program to compile and run without errors?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"int main() {return 0;}\"",
            "choices": [
                "main()",
                "int main() {return 0;}",
                "main() { }",
                "main() { ; }"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 13,
            "question": "\"What is optional in a function declaration?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"parameter names\"",
            "choices": [
                "data type of parameters",
                "return type of function",
                "parameter names",
                "number of parameters"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 14,
            "question": "\"C treats all devices, such as the display and the keyboard, as files. Which file opens automatically when a program executes?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"stdout\"",
            "choices": [
                "stdout",
                "stdio.h",
                "default.h",
                "string.h"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 15,
            "question": "\"In which segment does dynamic memory allocation takes place?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"heap\"",
            "choices": [
                "BSS Segment",
                "stack",
                "heap",
                "data segment"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 16,
            "question": "\"Which function do you use to deallocate memory?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"free()\"",
            "choices": [
                "dalloc()",
                "dealloc()",
                "release()",
                "free()"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 17,
            "question": "\"In C language what are the basic building blocks that are constructed together to write a program?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"tokens\"",
            "choices": [
                "keywords",
                "identifiers",
                "tokens",
                "functions"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 18,
            "question": "\"When is memory for a variable allocated?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"during the declaration of the variable\"",
            "choices": [
                "during the assigment of the variable",
                "during the initialization of the variable",
                "during the declaration of the variable",
                "during the definition of the variable"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 19,
            "question": "\"C uses the call by value method to pass arguments to functions. How can you invoke the call by reference method?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"by using pointers\"",
            "choices": [
                "by using pointers",
                "by declaring functions separately from defining them",
                "by using recursive functions",
                "by using global variables"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 20,
            "question": "\"A union allows you to store different `___` in the same `___`.\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"Data types; Memory space\"",
            "choices": [
                "Objects; Structure",
                "Variables; Declaration",
                "Data types; Memory space",
                "Arrays; Header file"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 21,
            "question": "\"What is the output of this program?\"",
            "body": "```c\nmain() {\n    char c1='a' , c2='A';\n    int i=c2-c1;\n    printf(\"%d\", i);\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"-32\"",
            "choices": [
                "32",
                "Runtime error",
                "-32",
                "0"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 22,
            "question": "\"What is the difference between scanf() and sscanf() functions?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"The scanf() function reads formatted data from the keyboard; The sscanf() function reads formatted input from a string.\"",
            "choices": [
                "The scanf() function reads data formatted as a string; The sscanf() function reads string input from the screen.",
                "The scanf() function reads formatted data from the keyboard; The sscanf() function reads formatted input from a string.",
                "The scanf() function reads string data from the keyboard; The sscanf() function reads string data from a string.",
                "The scanf() function reads formatted data from a file; The sscanf() function reads input from a selected string"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 23,
            "question": "\"What is not a valid command with this declaration?\"",
            "body": "```c\nchar *string[20] = { \"one\", \"two\", \"three\"};\n```",
            "answer": "\"`printf(\"%s\", string[1][2]);`\"",
            "choices": [
                "`printf(\"%c\", string[1][2]);`",
                "`printf(\"%s\", string[1][2]);`",
                "`printf(\"%s\", string[1]);`",
                "`printf(string[1]);`"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 24,
            "question": "\"What is the expression player->name equivalent to?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"`(*player).name`\"",
            "choices": [
                "`player.name`",
                "`(*player).name`",
                "`*player.name`",
                "`player.*name`"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 25,
            "question": "\"Which program will compile and run without errors?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\nmain() {\nfor(i=0; i<10; i++) ;\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nmain() {\nint i=0;\nfor(; i<10; i++) ;\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nmain() {\nint i;\nfor(i=0; i<j; i++) ;\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nmain() {\nint i;\nfor (i= 10; i<10; i++)\n}\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 26,
            "question": "\"What does this function call return?\"",
            "body": "```c\n1 main() { float x = f1(10, 5); }\n2 float f1(int a, int b) { return (a/b); }\n```",
            "answer": "\"a compiler error\"",
            "choices": [
                "2",
                "2.000000",
                "a runtime error",
                "a compiler error"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 27,
            "question": "\"What does this program create?\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include <stdio.h>\nint main() {\n    int *p = NULL;\n    return 0;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"a NULL pointer\"",
            "choices": [
                "a runtime error",
                "a NULL pointer",
                "a compile error",
                "a void pointer"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 28,
            "question": "\"What is an alternative way to write the expression (\\*x).y?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"x->y\"",
            "choices": [
                "There is no equivalent.",
                "x->y",
                "\\*x->y",
                "y->x"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 29,
            "question": "\"Compile time errors are static errors that can be found where in the code?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"in declarations and definitions\"",
            "choices": [
                "in declarations and definitions",
                "in functions and expressions",
                "in syntax and semantics",
                "in objects and statements"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 30,
            "question": "\"File input and output (I/O) in C is heavily based on the way it is done `___`?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"in Unix\"",
            "choices": [
                "in Unix",
                "in C++",
                "in C#",
                "in DOS"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 31,
            "question": "\"What does the strcmp(str1, str2); function return?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"0 if str1 and str2 are the same, a negative number if str1 is less than str2, a positive number if str1 is greater than str2\"",
            "choices": [
                "0 if str1 and str2 are the same, a negative number if str1 is less than str2, a positive number if str1 is greater than str2",
                "true (1) if str1 and str2 are the same, false (0) if str1 and str2 are not the same",
                "true (1) if str1 and str2 are the same, NULL if str1 and str2 are not the same",
                "0 if str1 and str2 are the same, a negative number if str2 is less than str1, a positive number if str2 is greater than str1"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 32,
            "question": "\"What is the output of this program?\"",
            "body": "```c\nint a=10, b=20;\nint f1(a) { return(a*b); }\nmain() {\nprintf(\"%d\", f1(5));\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"100\"",
            "choices": [
                "100",
                "200",
                "5",
                "50"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 33,
            "question": "\"Which is _not_ a correct way to declare a string variable?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"`char string = \"Hello World\";`\"",
            "choices": [
                "`char *string = \"Hello World\";`",
                "`char string = \"Hello World\";`",
                "`char string[20] = {'H', 'e', 'l', 'l', 'o', ' ', 'W', 'o', 'r', 'l', 'd'};`",
                "`char string[] = \"Hello World\";`"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 34,
            "question": "\"Which choice is an include guard for the header file mylib.h?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\n#ifdef MYLIB_H\n#undef MYLIB_H\n\n// mylib.h content\n\n#endif /* MYLIB_H */\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\n#ifndef MYLIB_H\n#define MYLIB_H\n\n// mylib.h content\n\n#endif /* MYLIB_H */\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\n#define MYLIB_H\n#include \"mylib.h\"\n\n#undef MYLIB_H\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\n#ifdef MYLIB_H\n#define MYLIB_H\n\n// mylib.h content\n\n#endif /* MYLIB_H */\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 35,
            "question": "\"How many times does the code inside the while loop get executed in this program?\"",
            "body": "```c\nmain(){\n int x=1;\n while(x++<100){\n    x*=x;\n    if(x<10) continue;\n    if(x>50) break;\n }\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"3\"",
            "choices": [
                "100",
                "3",
                "5",
                "50"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 36,
            "question": "\"File input and output (I/O) in C is done through what?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"function calls\"",
            "choices": [
                "syntax-driven components",
                "native interfaces",
                "system objects",
                "function calls"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 37,
            "question": "\"Directives are translated by the?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"Pre-processor\"",
            "choices": [
                "Pre-processor",
                "Compiler",
                "Linker",
                "Editor"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 38,
            "question": "\"The main loop structures in C programming are the for loop, the while loop, and which other loop?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"do...while\"",
            "choices": [
                "do...while",
                "for...in",
                "repeat...until",
                "do...until"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 39,
            "question": "\"By default, C Functions are what type of functions?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"library\"",
            "choices": [
                "global",
                "static",
                "library",
                "system"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 40,
            "question": "\"You have written a function that you want to include as a member of structure a. How is such as structure member defined?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\nstruct a {\nvoid *f1;\n};\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nstruct a {\nvoid (*f1)();\n};\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nstruct a {\n*(void *f1)();\n};\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nstruct a {\nvoid *f1();\n};\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 41,
            "question": "\"A Stack data structure allows all data operations at one end only, making it what kind of an implementation?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"LIFO\"",
            "choices": [
                "FIFO",
                "LIFO",
                "LILO",
                "LOLI"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 42,
            "question": "\"What does this program display?\"",
            "body": "```c\nmain(){\n    char *p = \"ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ\";\n    int i;\n    for (i=0;i<5;i++) *p++; *p++;\n    printf(\"%c\",*p++);\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"G\"",
            "choices": [
                "K",
                "M",
                "H",
                "G"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 43,
            "question": "\"Describe the relationship between lvalue and rvalue.\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"An lvalue may appear on the left-hand or right-hand side of an assignment; an rvalue may appear only on the right-hand side.\"",
            "choices": [
                "An lvalue may appear only on the left-hand side of an assignment; an rvalue may appear only on the right-hand side.",
                "An lvalue may appear only on the left-hand side of an assignment; an rvalue may appear on either the left-hand or right-hand side.",
                "An lvalue and an rvalue may appear on either left-hand or right-hand side of an assignment.",
                "An lvalue may appear on the left-hand or right-hand side of an assignment; an rvalue may appear only on the right-hand side."
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 44,
            "question": "\"Which operator is used to access the address of a variable?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"`&`\"",
            "choices": [
                "`%`",
                "`**`",
                "`*`",
                "`&`"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 45,
            "question": "\"Which add function properly returns the updated value of result?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\nvoid add (int a, int b, int *result)\n{\n*result = a+b;\n}\n\nmain()\n{\nint a = 10;\nint b = 20;\nint result = 0;\n\nadd(a,b,&result);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nvoid add (int a, int b, int result)\n{\nresult = a+b;\n}\n\nmain()\n{\nint a = 10;\nint b = 20;\nint result = 0;\n\nadd(a,b,result);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nvoid add (int a, int b, int *result)\n{\nresult = a+b;\n}\n\nmain()\n{\nint a = 10;\nint b = 20;\nint result = 0;\n\nadd(a,b,result);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nvoid add (int *a, int *b, int *result)\n{\nresult = a+b;\n}\n\nmain()\n{\nint a = 10;\nint b = 20;\nint result = 0;\n\nadd(*a,*b,*result);\n}\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 46,
            "question": "\"Consider the number of the Fibonacci series below 100: 0,1,1,2,3,5,8,13,21,34,55,89. Which piece of code outputs the sequence?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\nvoid fibonacci(int a, int b)\n{\nint c = a+b;\n\nif(a>100)\nreturn;\n\nprintf(\"%d\", a);\n\nfibonacci(a,b);\n}\n\nint main()\n{\nfibonacci(0,1);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nvoid fibonacci(int a, int b)\n{\nint c = a+b;\n\nif(a>100)\nreturn;\n\nprintf(\"%d\", b);\n\nfibonacci(a,c);\n}\n\nint main()\n{\nfibonacci(0,1);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nvoid fibonacci(int a, int b)\n{\nint c = a+b;\n\nif(a>100)\nreturn;\n\nprintf(\"%d\", a);\n\nfibonacci(b,c);\n}\n\nint main()\n{\nfibonacci(0,1);\n}\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nvoid fibonacci(int a, int b)\n{\nint c = a+b;\n\nif(a>100)\nreturn;\n\nprintf(\"%d\", c);\n\nfibonacci(b,c);\n}\n\nint main()\n{\nfibonacci(0,1);\n}\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 47,
            "question": "\"Which is _not_ a storage class specifier?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"`intern`\"",
            "choices": [
                "`intern`",
                "`extern`",
                "`register`",
                "`static`"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 48,
            "question": "\"Which line of code, after execution, results in `i` having the value of 1?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"`for(i=1; i==10; i++);`\"",
            "choices": [
                "`for(i=1; i<=1; i++);`",
                "`for(i=1; i=10; i++);`",
                "`for(i=1; i==10; i++);`",
                "`for(i=10; i>=1; i--);`"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 49,
            "question": "\"What is the value of variable c at the end of this program?\"",
            "body": "```\n1 main() {\n2   int a, b, c;\n3   a=10; b=50;\n4   c=a * b % a;\n5 }\n```",
            "answer": "\"0\"",
            "choices": [
                "50",
                "5",
                "0",
                "500"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 50,
            "question": "\"What is _not_ one of the basic data types in C\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"array\"",
            "choices": [
                "long double",
                "unsigned char",
                "array",
                "float"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 51,
            "question": "\"What is the member access operator for a structure?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\".\"",
            "choices": [
                ",",
                "[]",
                ".",
                ":"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 52,
            "question": "\"What standard data type provides the smallest storage size and can be used in computations?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"char\"",
            "choices": [
                "char",
                "float",
                "int",
                "short"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 53,
            "question": "\"what does the ctype tolower() function do?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"It converts an uppercase letter of the alphabet to lowercase.\"",
            "choices": [
                "It returns TRUE for lowercase letters of the alphabet.",
                "It ensures that text output uses only ASCII values (0 through 127).",
                "It returns FALSE for lowercase letters of the alphabet.",
                "It converts an uppercase letter of the alphabet to lowercase."
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 54,
            "question": "\"Void pointer _vptr_ is assigned the address of float variable _g_. What is a valid way to dereference _vptr_ to assign its pointed value to a float variable named _f_ later in the program?\"",
            "body": "```c\nfloat g;\nvoid *vptr=&g;\n```",
            "answer": "\"`f=*(float *)vptr;`\"",
            "choices": [
                "`f=(float *)vptr;`",
                "`f=*(float *)vptr;`",
                "`f=*(float)vptr;`",
                "`f=(float)*vptr;`"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 55,
            "question": "\"The dynamic memory allocation functions are defined in which system header file ?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"stdlib.h\"",
            "choices": [
                "stdio.h",
                "stdlib.h",
                "limits.h",
                "stddef.h"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 56,
            "question": "\"A function is a set of **\\_**.\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"statements\"",
            "choices": [
                "declarations",
                "statements",
                "variables",
                "objects"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 57,
            "question": "\"How are static functions different from global functions?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"Static functions can be accessed only in the file where they are declared.\"",
            "choices": [
                "Static functions must be declared in advance of being defined.",
                "Static functions must be declared is a separate header file.",
                "Static functions always return the same value.",
                "Static functions can be accessed only in the file where they are declared."
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 58,
            "question": "\"Which code example creates the string \"Hello Mars\" in storage buffer `hello`.\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\nchar hello[25];\nstrcpy(hello, \"Hello \");\nstrcpy(hello, \"Mars\");\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nchar hello[25];\nchar *p;\nstrcpy(hello, \"Hello World\");\np = hello;\np +=6;\nstrcpy(p, \"Mars\");\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nchar *hello;\nstrcpy(hello, \"Hello World\");\nhello+=6;\nstrcpy(hello, \"Mars\");\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\nchar hello[25];\nstrcpy(hello, \"Hello World\");\nstrcpy(*hello[6], \"Mars\");\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 59,
            "question": "\"If you use the fopen() function with the \"a\" mode, what happens if the named file doesn't exist?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"The file is created and opened for writing.\"",
            "choices": [
                "The file is created and opened for reading.",
                "The file is created and opened for writing.",
                "The fopen() function returns a NULL indicating that the operation has failed.",
                "The file is created and opened for both writing and reading"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 60,
            "question": "\"What does this function return?\"",
            "body": "```c\nint fl(int a, int b) { return(a>b?a:b); }\n```",
            "answer": "\"the greater value of the two passed parameters\"",
            "choices": [
                "compiler error",
                "the smaller value of the two passed parameters",
                "runtime error",
                "the greater value of the two passed parameters"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 61,
            "question": "\"Which option is a valid function name?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"draw_star()\"",
            "choices": [
                "draw_star()",
                "5times()",
                "upper-limit()",
                "auto()"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 62,
            "question": "\"What is not a valid type definition of a structure that contains x and y coordinates as integers, and that can be used as shown for the variable named point?\"",
            "body": "```c\ncoord point;\npoint.x = 9;\npoint.y = 3;\n```",
            "answer": "\":\"",
            "choices": [
                ":",
                "```c\nstruct coord{\nint x;\nint y;\n};\ntypedef struct coord coord;\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\ntypedef struct coord{\nint x;\nint y;\n};\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\ntypedef struct coord{\nint x;\nint y;\n} coord;\n```",
                ":",
                "```c\ntypedef struct{\nint x;\nint y;\n} coord;\n```"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 63,
            "question": "\"What is the output of the below program?\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include <stdio.h>\n#if X == 3\n    #define Y 3\n#else\n    #define Y 5\n#endif\n\nint main()\n{\n    printf(\"%d\", Y);\n    return 0;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"5\"",
            "choices": [
                "3",
                "5",
                "3 or 5 depending on input",
                "Compile time error"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 64,
            "question": "\"What do the functions malloc() and calloc() allocate?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"dynamic memory\"",
            "choices": [
                "reallocatged memory",
                "static memeory",
                "dynamic memory",
                "fragmented memory"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 65,
            "question": "\"You need to determine if a string variable is a substring of another string. Which standard C library function do you use?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"strstr(str1, str2);\"",
            "choices": [
                "substr(str1, str2);",
                "strstr(str1, str2);",
                "substring(str1, str2);",
                "strspn(str1, str2);"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 66,
            "question": "\"Find the output of the program?\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include <stdio.h>\n\n#define L 10\nint main(){\n    int a =10;\n    switch (a,a<<2){\n        case L:printf(\"a==L\");     break;\n        case L*2 : printf(\"a = L* 2\\n\");     break;\n        case L*4 : printf(\"a = L* 4\\n\");    break;\n        default: printf(\"Error\\n\");\n    }\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"`a=L*4`\"",
            "choices": [
                "`a=L*2`",
                "`a=L`",
                "`Error`",
                "`a=L*4`"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 67,
            "question": "\"Predict the output of the following code when the **interger** variables x is initialized to 10,y to 2 and z to 0.\"",
            "body": "```c\nz = x + y * x + 10 / 2 * x;\nprintf(\"value is =%d\",z);\n```",
            "answer": "\"80\"",
            "choices": [
                "80",
                "170",
                "31.5",
                "6"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 68,
            "question": "\"What will be the output of the following code snippet?\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include <stdio.h>\nvoid solve() {\n    int x = 2;\n    printf(\"%d\", (x << 1) + (x >> 1));\n}\nint main() {\n    solve();\n\treturn 0;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"5\"",
            "choices": [
                "5",
                "4",
                "2",
                "1"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 69,
            "question": "\"What is the output of this program?\"",
            "body": "```c\nint a=20, b=10;\nint f1(a) {\n    return(a*b);\n}\nmain() {\n    printf(\"%d\", f1(5));\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"50\"",
            "choices": [
                "100",
                "200",
                "5",
                "50"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 70,
            "question": "\"What is /0 character ?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"NULL Character\"",
            "choices": [
                "String",
                "NULL Character",
                "ZERO",
                "Variable"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 71,
            "question": "\"What is correct output for follwing code ?1\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include&lt;stdio.h&gt;\n#include&lt;conio.h&gt;\nmain()\n{\n     int a=10, b=20;\n     clrscr();\n     printf(\"Before swapping a=%d b=%d\",a,b);\n     a=a+b;\n     b=a-b;\n     a=a-b;\n     printf(\"nAfter swapping a=%d b=%d\",a,b);\n     getch();\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"Before a=10 b=20 , After a=20 b=10\"",
            "choices": [
                "Before a=10 b=20 , After a=10 b=10",
                "Before a=10 b=10 , After a=20 b=10",
                "Before a=10 b=20 , After a=20 b=20",
                "Before a=10 b=20 , After a=20 b=10"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 72,
            "question": "\"What is Incorrect option that explain # pragma directive ?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"#pragma startup don't allows us to specify functions called upon program startup.\"",
            "choices": [
                "#pragma exit allows us to specify functions called upon program exit.",
                "This is a preprocessor directive that can be used to turn on or off certain features.",
                "#pragma startup don't allows us to specify functions called upon program startup.",
                "It is of two types #pragma startup, #pragma exit and pragma warn."
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 73,
            "question": "\"What will be the output of the following code snippet?\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include <stdio.h>\nunion School {\n    int age, rollNo;\n    double marks;\n};\nvoid solve() {\n    union School sc;\n    sc.age = 19;\n    sc.rollNo = 82;\n    sc.marks = 19.04;\n    printf(\"%d\", (int)sizeof(sc));\n}\nint main() {\n    solve();\n\treturn 0;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"8\"",
            "choices": [
                "2",
                "4",
                "8",
                "10"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 74,
            "question": "\"What will be the output of the following code snippet?\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include <stdio.h>\nstruct School {\n    int age, rollNo;\n};\nvoid solve() {\n    struct School sc;\n    sc.age = 19;\n    sc.rollNo = 82;\n    printf(\"%d %d\", sc.age, sc.rollNo);\n}\nint main() {\n    solve();\n\treturn 0;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"19 82\"",
            "choices": [
                "19 82",
                "Compilation Error",
                "82 19",
                "None of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 75,
            "question": "\"What is the output of the following code snippet?\"",
            "body": "```c\nint main() {\n\tint sum = 2 + 4 / 2 + 6 * 2;\n\tprintf(\"%d\", sum);\n\treturn 0;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"16\"",
            "choices": [
                "2",
                "15",
                "16",
                "18"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 76,
            "question": "\"What does the following declaration mean?\"",
            "body": "```\nint (*ptr)[10];\n```",
            "answer": "\"ptr is a pointer to an array of 10 integers\"",
            "choices": [
                "ptr is array of pointers to 10 integers",
                "ptr is a pointer to an array of 10 integers",
                "ptr is an array of 10 integers",
                "ptr is an pointer to array"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 77,
            "question": "\"What will be the output of the following code snippet?\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include <stdio.h>\nvoid change(int,int);\nint main()\n{\n   int a=10,b=20;\n   change(a,b); //calling a function by passing the values of variables.\n   printf(\"Value of a is: %d\",a);\n   printf(\"\\n\");\n   printf(\"Value of b is: %d\",b);\n   return 0;\n}\nvoid change(int x,int y)\n{\n   x=13;\n   y=17;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"10,20\"",
            "choices": [
                "10,20",
                "10,10",
                "20,20",
                "20,10"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 78,
            "question": "\"Choose true or false.When variable is created in C, a memory address is assigned to the variable.\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"True\"",
            "choices": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 79,
            "question": "\"What does the following fragment of C-program print?\"",
            "body": "```c\n#include <stdio.h>\n\nint main()\n{\n    char c[] = \"GATE2011\";\n\n    char *p = c;\n\n    printf(\"%s\", p + p[3] -p[1]);\n\n    return 0;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"2011\"",
            "choices": [
                "GATE 2011",
                "E2011",
                "2011",
                "01"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 80,
            "question": "\"What is the output of the following code snippet?\"",
            "body": "```c\nint main() {\n\tint a = 5, b = 6, c;\n\tc = a++ + ++b;\n\tprintf(\"%d %d %d\", a, b, c);\n\treturn 0;\n}\n```",
            "answer": "\"6 7 12\"",
            "choices": [
                "5 6 11",
                "6 7 12",
                "5 6 12",
                "6 6 12"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 81,
            "question": "\"What will be the output of the following C program segment?\"",
            "body": "```c\nchar inchar = 'A';\nswitch (inchar)\n{\ncase 'A' :\n\tprintf (\"choice A \\n\") ;\ncase 'B' :\n\tprintf (\"choice B \") ;\ncase 'C' :\ncase 'D' :\ncase 'E' :\ndefault:\n\tprintf (\"No Choice\") ;\n}\n\n```",
            "answer": "\"Choice A\"",
            "choices": [
                "No choice",
                "Choice A",
                "Choice A",
                "Program gives no output as it is erroneous"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 82,
            "question": "\"Which of the following is the correct syntax to print the message in C++ language?\"",
            "body": "",
            "answer": "\"cout <<\"Hello world!\";\"",
            "choices": [
                "Out <<\"Hello world!",
                "Cout << Hello world! ;",
                "cout <<\"Hello world!\";",
                "None of the above"
            ]
        },
        {
            "topic": "C (Programming Language)",
            "id": 83,
            "question": "\"String variable str1 has the value of \"abc\", and string variable str2 has the value \"xyz\". What are the values of str1 and str2 after this statement is executed?\"",
            "body": "```c\nstrcpy(str1, str2);\n```",
            "answer": "\"str1: \"xyz\" ; str2: \"xyz\"\"",
            "choices": [
                "str1: \"xyz\" ; str2: \"xyz\"",
                "str1: \"abc\" ; str2: \"xyz\"",
                "str1: \"xyz\" ; str2: \"abc\"",
                "str1: \"abc\" ; str2: \"abc\""
            ]
        }
    ]
}